your favorite athlete closes in for a victorious win
你最喜欢的运动员即将取得胜利
the crowd holds its breath
人群屏住呼吸
and at the crucial moment
而在关键时刻
she misses the shot
她射偏了
that competitor just experienced the
那个竞争对手刚刚经历了
phenomenon known as choking
被称为窒息的现象
where despite months
尽管几个月
even years of practice
甚至多年的实践
a person fails right when it matters most
一个人在最重要的时候失败了
choking is common in sports
窒息在运动中很常见
where performance often occurs under
性能经常发生在
intense pressure and depends on key moments  and yet
压力很大，取决于关键时刻，然而
performance anxiety also haunts public speakers
表演焦虑也困扰着公众演讲者
contestants in spelling bees
拼字比赛的参赛者
and even world famous musicians
甚至世界著名音乐家
most people intuitively blame it on their nerves
大多数人本能地将此归咎于他们的神经
but why does being nervous
但为什么紧张
undermine expert performance
破坏专家绩效
there are two sets of theories
有两套理论
which both say that primarily
两者都说主要是
choking under pressure boils down to focus
在压力下窒息归结为专注
first  there are the distraction theories
首先是分心理论
these suggest that performance suffers when
这些表明，当
the mind is preoccupied with worries
心事重重
doubts or fears
疑虑或恐惧
instead of focusing its attention
而不是集中注意力
on performing the task at hand
执行手头的任务
when relevant and irrelevant thoughts
当相关和不相关的想法
compete for the same attention
同流合污
something has to give
有些东西必须付出
the brain can only process so
大脑只能这样处理
much information at once
多信息一次
tasks that challenge working memory
挑战工作记忆的任务
the mental scratchpad we use to temporarily
我们暂时用来
store phone numbers and grocery lists
商店电话号码和杂货清单
are especially vulnerable to pressure
特别容易受到压力的影响
in a 2,004 study
在一项2004年的研究中
a group of university students were
一群大学生
asked to perform math problems  some easy
要求做一些简单的数学题
others more complex and memory intensive
其他更复杂和内存密集型
half the students completed both problem types
一半的学生完成了两种问题类型
with nothing at stake while the others
没有任何危险，而其他人
completed them when calm and under pressure
在平静和压力下完成它们
while everyone did well on the easy problems
虽然每个人都在简单的问题上做得很好
those who were stressed performed worse on
那些有压力的人表现得更差
the more difficult memory intensive tasks
更困难的内存密集型任务
explicit monitoring theories make up the second
显式监控理论构成第二
group of explanations for choking under pressure
压力下窒息的一组解释
they're concerned with how pressure can cause
他们担心压力会导致
people to overanalyze the task at hand
人们过度分析手头的任务
here
这里
the logic goes that once a skill becomes automatic
逻辑是，一旦技能变成自动的
thinking about its precise mechanics
思考它的精确机制
interferes with your ability to do it
干扰了你做这件事的能力
tasks we do unconsciously seem to be most
我们不知不觉中完成的任务似乎是最重要的
vulnerable to this kind of choking
易受这种窒息的影响
a study on competitive golfers compared their
一项关于有竞争力的高尔夫球手的研究
performance when instructed to simply focus on putting
当被指示简单地专注于推杆时的表现
as accurately as possible versus when they were primed
尽可能准确地对比他们准备好的时间
to be acutely aware of the mechanics of their putting
敏锐地意识到他们推杆的机制
stroke
中风
golfers usually perform this action subconsciously
高尔夫球手通常下意识地进行这个动作
so those who suddenly tuned in to the
所以那些突然调到
precise details of their own moves also
他们自己动作的精确细节也
became worse at making accurate shots
变得更不擅长准确投篮
choking may not be inevitable for everyone though
虽然并不是每个人都不可避免地会窒息
research suggests that some are
研究表明有些是
more susceptible than others
比其他人更容易受到影响
especially those who are self conscious  anxious
尤其是那些自我意识焦虑的人
and afraid of being judged negatively by others  so
害怕被别人负面评价所以
how can we avoid choking when it really counts
当真正重要的时候，我们如何避免窒息？
first  it helps to practice under stressful conditions
首先，它有助于在压力条件下练习
in a study on expert dart players
在一项关于专业飞镖运动员的研究中
researchers found that those who hadn't practiced
研究人员发现那些没有练习过的人
under stress performed worse when anxious compared to
在压力下，焦虑时的表现比
those who had become accustomed to pressure
那些习惯了压力的人
secondly  many performers extol the virtues
其次，许多表演者赞美美德
of a pre performance routine
演出前的例行公事
whether it's taking a few deep breaths
不管是深呼吸几次
repeating a cue word
重复提示词
or doing a rhythmic sequence of movements
或者做一系列有节奏的动作
studies on golfing
高尔夫研究
bowling and water polo find that short
保龄球和水球找那个短
rituals can lead to more consistent and
仪式可以导致更一致和
accurate performance under pressure
压力下准确的性能
and thirdly
第三
researchers have shown that having an external
研究人员已经表明，有一个外部的
focus on the ultimate goal works better than
专注于最终目标比
an internal focus where someone is tuned into
一个内部焦点，某人被调到
the mechanics of what they're doing
他们正在做的事情的机制
a study of experienced golfers revealed that those
一项对有经验的高尔夫球手的研究表明
who hit chip shots while focused on the flight of
谁在专注于飞行的同时击中了筹码
the ball performed significantly better than those
球的表现明显好于那些
who focused on the motion of their arms
他们专注于手臂的运动
so perhaps we can modify that age old saying
所以也许我们可以修改那句古老的谚语
practice under pressure with focus and with that
在压力下集中注意力练习
glorious end goal in sight makes perfect
眼前的光荣目标造就完美
for a nail biting example of
一个咬指甲的例子
persevering under pressure
顶住压力
we highly recommend The Boys in the boat
我们强烈推荐船上的男孩
it tells the gripping true story of nine
它讲述了九个人扣人心弦的真实故事
American rowers and their quest for gold at
美国赛艇运动员和他们对金牌的追求
the 1936 Olympics in Nazi Germany
1936年纳粹德国奥运会
you can download an audio version of this
你可以下载这个的音频版本
book for free at audible com teded
在audible com teded免费预订
every free trial started through this link
每个免费试用都通过此链接开始
helps support Teded's nonprofit mission
帮助支持Teded的非盈利使命